<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>NotInKansasNow</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://notinkansasnow.com/</id><updated>2011-07-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Room temperature and narrow intersubband electroluminescence from ZnCdSe/ZnCdMgSe quantum cascade laser structures</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2011/07/room-temperature-and-narrow-intersubband-electroluminescence-from-zncdsezncdmgse-quantum-cascade-laser-structures/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-07-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Kale Franz</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2011-07-29:publication/2011/07/room-temperature-and-narrow-intersubband-electroluminescence-from-zncdsezncdmgse-quantum-cascade-laser-structures/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We report ZnCdSe/ZnCdMgSe Quantum Cascade structures with “two-phonon” and
“bound-to-continuum” active region designs. The electroluminescence shows more
than 3 times higher luminescence efficiency and 40% narrower linewidth (&amp;lt;30 meV)
than previous reports. The measured turn-on voltage matches closely the
calculated value, indicating the improved electron transport characteristics in
these structures. A waveguide design suitable for mode confinement in this
material system is also presented, which resulted in a structure with a single
narrow electroluminescence peak for all temperatures from 80 to 300 K.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="QCLs"></category><category term="II-VI semiconductors"></category><category term="lasers"></category></entry><entry><title>Optical Properties of Heavily Doped n-type CdSe Quantum Dots for Intersubband Device Applications</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2007/09/optical-properties-of-heavily-doped-n-type-cdse-quantum-dots-for-intersubband-device-applications/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-09-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Kale Franz</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2007-09-06:publication/2007/09/optical-properties-of-heavily-doped-n-type-cdse-quantum-dots-for-intersubband-device-applications/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this research, interband and intersubband optical properties of heavily doped
n-type CdSe quantum dots were investigated by temperature dependent
photoluminescence (PL) spectroscopy, picosecond time-resolved PL spectroscopy
and Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy. Two doped and one undoped
CdSe quantum dot samples with multiple QD layers were grown over ZnCdMgSe
barrier layers on InP (001) substrate by molecular beam epitaxy. Heavy doping
leads to decreasing of activation energy of nonradiative recombination centers,
however, does not affect the luminescence efficiency of doped quantum dots. Time
resolved PL experiments show that the PL decay times of the doped samples have
weak dependence on dot size and are much longer than that of the undoped sample.
The two doped CdSe QD samples show strong Intersubband IR absorption that peaked
at 2.54 μm, 2.69 μm and 3.51 μm.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="quantum dots"></category><category term="II-VI semiconductors"></category><category term="intersubband optical transitions"></category></entry><entry><title>Intersubband absorption in CdSe/ZnCdMgSe self-assembled quantum dot multi-layers</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2007/02/intersubband-absorption-in-cdsezncdmgse-self-assembled-quantum-dot-multi-layers/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-02-15T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Kale Franz</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2007-02-15:publication/2007/02/intersubband-absorption-in-cdsezncdmgse-self-assembled-quantum-dot-multi-layers/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The authors report the observation of intersubband absorption in multilayers of
CdSe/Zn&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;Cd&lt;sub&gt;y&lt;/sub&gt;Mg&lt;sub&gt;1−x−y&lt;/sub&gt;Se self-assembled quantum
dots. The samples were grown by molecular beam epitaxy on InP substrates. For
samples with the CdSe dot layers doped with Cl and with the deposited CdSe
equivalent layer thickness between 5.2 and 6.9 ML, peak absorption between 2.5
and 3.5 µm was observed. These materials are promising for intersubband devices
operating in the mid- and near-infrared ranges.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="quantum dots"></category><category term="II-VI semiconductors"></category><category term="intersubband optical transitions"></category></entry><entry><title>Optical characterization of intersubband transitions in ZnxCd1−xSe/Znx'Cdy'Mg1−x'−y'Se multiple quantum well structures by contactless electroreflectance</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2006/12/optical-characterization-of-intersubband-transitions-in-znxcd1-xseznxcdymg1-x-yse-multiple-quantum-well-structures-by-contactless-electroreflectance/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2006-12-15T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Kale Franz</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2006-12-15:publication/2006/12/optical-characterization-of-intersubband-transitions-in-znxcd1-xseznxcdymg1-x-yse-multiple-quantum-well-structures-by-contactless-electroreflectance/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Contactless electroreflectance was measured at room temperature to characterize
a wide range of the possible optical transitions in
Zn&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;Cd&lt;sub&gt;1−x&lt;/sub&gt;Se/Zn&lt;sub&gt;x'&lt;/sub&gt;Cd&lt;sub&gt;y'&lt;/sub&gt;Mg&lt;sub&gt;1−x'−y'&lt;/sub&gt;Se
multi-quantum-well structures grown by molecular beam epitaxy. Based on these
measurements, the authors predict and then verify the anticipated intersubband
transition energies. They investigate a representative
Zn&lt;sub&gt;0.5&lt;/sub&gt;Cd&lt;sub&gt;0.5&lt;/sub&gt;Se/Zn&lt;sub&gt;0.20&lt;/sub&gt;Cd&lt;sub&gt;0.19&lt;/sub&gt;Mg&lt;sub&gt;0.61&lt;/sub&gt;Se
structure, for which the &lt;em&gt;E1&lt;/em&gt;-&lt;em&gt;E2&lt;/em&gt; transition energy is predicted to be 178 meV
(6.97 µm). Intersubband absorption using Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy
exhibits a peak at 180 meV (6.89 µm), in excellent agreement with the
contactless electroreflectance measurements.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="II-VI semiconductors"></category><category term="intersubband optical transitions"></category></entry><entry><title>A dual-wavelength quantum cascade laser with two optical transitions in each active region</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2006/05/a-dual-wavelength-quantum-cascade-laser-with-two-optical-transitions-in-each-active-region/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2006-05-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Kale Franz</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2006-05-07:publication/2006/05/a-dual-wavelength-quantum-cascade-laser-with-two-optical-transitions-in-each-active-region/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We report on a novel quantum cascade laser design that utilizes wide active
region quantum wells to create a lasing transition between the second- and
first-excited states of the constituent wells. Electroluminescence and lasing
spectra confirm the presence of the optical transition at the expected energy,
but also show the conventional transition between energy levels resulting from
excited and ground states of the original quantum wells. As a result, the laser
produces simultaneous dual-wavelength emission at 8.2 μm and 9.3 μm.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="QCLs"></category><category term="lasers"></category></entry><entry><title>Carbon single-wall nanotube growth in a volumetrically confined arc discharge system</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2004/08/carbon-single-wall-nanotube-growth-in-a-volumetrically-confined-arc-discharge-system/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2004-08-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Kale Franz</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2004-08-01:publication/2004/08/carbon-single-wall-nanotube-growth-in-a-volumetrically-confined-arc-discharge-system/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Carbon nanotubes hold significant promise for a vast number of materials
applications due to their unique mechanical, electrical, and gas storage
properties. Although carbon single-wall nanotubes (SWNTs) have been synthesized
since 1993 by the arc discharge method, and numerous other synthesis methods
have since been developed, no method has yet produced 100% pure carbon
nanotubes. Instead, a significant amount of impurities—various carbon structures
and metal catalysts—are present in the raw soot. While arc discharge was the
first method for SWNT synthesis, it also produces more impure raw soot in
comparison to the more recently developed laser vaporization, which has produced
the purest raw soot to date but is much slower. Geometry and thermal gradient
are appreciably different between traditional arc discharge systems and laser
vaporization systems. We report that, by incorporating some characteristics
inherent to a laser vaporization system into an arc discharge system,
improvement in the yield of SWNT raw soot may be achieved. This is accomplished
by confining the arc within a 50 mm diameter quartz tube, similar to laser
vaporization. We find through transmission electron microscopy and Raman
spectroscopy that SWNTs are made in significant numbers in this confined arc
discharge system, comparable to laser vaporization synthesized material. Further
study is, however, required to prove reproducibility and attain an exact value
for the purity of the produced raw soot.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="carbon nanotubes"></category></entry><entry><title>DNA Dilemma: A perspective on U.S. Patent and Trademark Office philosophy concerning life patents</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2002/08/dna-dilemma-a-perspective-on-us-patent-and-trademark-office-philosophy-concerning-life-patents/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2002-08-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Kale Franz</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2002-08-01:publication/2002/08/dna-dilemma-a-perspective-on-us-patent-and-trademark-office-philosophy-concerning-life-patents/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The lack of a solid set of criteria for determining patentability of subject
matter—particularly subject matter dealing with life—has recently been of
increasing public concern in the United States. Alarm for patent practices
related to life systems ranges from patents being granted on
biochemical processes and the knowledge of these processes to the patenting of
entire organisms. One of the most volatile concerns is the patenting of human
genes or parts of genes since this genetic material is the basic informational
molecule for all life. Current patent law, legislated in 1952, has been
interpreted by the U.S. Supreme Court to allow broad patents of DNA, biochemical
processes, and what are generally considered "inventions" of life systems.
Several issues are addressed in this paper regarding the unsound reasoning
underlying both the interpretation and execution of patent law. Lapses in logic
provide a gateway for businesses and individuals to take patenting to an
illogical and unworkable extreme. Patent Office disorder of this magnitude is
unnecessary and has great potential for harming the mission that the patent
office was designed to serve. Recently disclosed patent-granting guidelines
suggest the United States Patent and Trademark Office is not upholding its
Constitutional responsibility of promoting the progress of science.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="patents"></category><category term="dna"></category></entry></feed>