<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>NotInKansasNow</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://notinkansasnow.com/</id><updated>2013-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Introducing uncolorblind</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/code/2013/05/introducing-uncolorblind/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Kale Franz</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2013-05-13:code/2013/05/introducing-uncolorblind/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm color blind. Or technically "color deficient." For example, most people can
see the &lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; in the color plate. I can't. (Yet I can study it
closely and point out individual dots that look green-ish, orange-ish, or
red-ish to me. Weird; I know.) So an &lt;em&gt;utlra&lt;/em&gt; valuable tool for me in the past
has been this &lt;a href="http://www.hikarun.com/e/"&gt;WhatColor&lt;/a&gt; app.
Not only does it provide the RGB and Hex values for
the color on your screen directly below your mouse, it also tells you the name
of the color. I'm working mostly on OS X now, and Apple's DigitalColor Meter
just doesn't compete (or have the color name feature). &lt;strong&gt;tl;dr&lt;/strong&gt;...I made my
own; it's called &lt;em&gt;uncolorblind&lt;/em&gt;, and it's all on
&lt;a href="https://github.com/kalefranz/uncolorblind"&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;. I'll also package up
distributable binaries at some point too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="color plate" src="/static/image/color_plate.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="code"></category><category term="color blind"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="qt"></category></entry><entry><title>On Contracting Software Development</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/code/2013/05/on-contracting-software-development/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Kale Franz</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2013-05-13:code/2013/05/on-contracting-software-development/</id><summary type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Assertion:&lt;/strong&gt; The company owns the code, not the contractor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're a contractor, why wouldn't you want to keep the actual source to
yourself?  You lock the company your contacting for into using your services in
perpetuity.  Good for the contractor; &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; bad for the procuring company.  My
guess is that less-than-competent and more "old school" contractors who aren't
able to keep up with technology's pace will push this tactic for their own job
security. But the contractor lock-in prevents the company from moving forward
with their product using another contractor if the relationship sours with the
current contractor.  It also prevents the company from transitioning away from
contract work to an in-house development team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of this document contains steps necessary to have the best chance for
getting quality code from a contractor.  I would consider each item mandatory.
There are also plenty of "nice to haves," but I want to keep this right now to
what I consider mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;You control the source control&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your contractor will use the source control system that you provide.  It is your
company's own source control system, and you give and revoke permissions to your
own repositories.  Use Git.  Everybody uses Git today.  If your contractor
complains that Git is "too hard," run away as fast as you can.  Create an account
on either &lt;a href="http://www.github.com"&gt;github.com&lt;/a&gt; or
&lt;a href="http://www.bitbucket.com"&gt;bitbucket.com&lt;/a&gt;.  Both are widely used and great
products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Demand documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation of the system that your contractor is designing should be part of
the deal.  Documented topics would include, for example,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thorough explanation of the system architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thorough documentation of any API layers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;code deployment &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Runbook"&gt;run book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like source code revision control, &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; should own the documentation and it
should be kept in a location that &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; control.  My recommendation is
Atlassian's &lt;a href="http://www.atlassian.com/software/confluence/overview/team-collaboration-software"&gt;Confluence&lt;/a&gt;
product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One critical part of quality software is readable and comprehensible source code.
Professional programmers in a team environment should be adept at writing in-code
comments where necessary and in general write code that is overall
self-documenting.  &lt;em&gt;Not all code is self documenting!  Writing self-documenting
code takes deliberate effort.  Just because code compiles, it is not therefore
"self-documenting"!!&lt;/em&gt;  Advice here would be to  require that every public
function (within reason, so exclude getters, setters, etc.) have a
language-relevant documentation block (docstring, javadoc, etc).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Source code tests&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professional programmers write unit tests.  To be sure that the code being
developed runs as it should, demand unit tests be written by the programmers as
part of the project.  &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Code_coverage"&gt;Code coverage&lt;/a&gt;
is a metric that describes what percent of your source code is "touched" or
covered by unit tests.  Include a code coverage stipulation as part of your
contract; a reasonable number is somewhere in the neighborhood of 80%.  Note
that there is a danger with using code coverage as a sole metric for test
quality.  From &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/695888/2127762"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; StackOverflow post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code coverage tells you what you definitely &lt;strong&gt;haven't&lt;/strong&gt; tested, not what you &lt;strong&gt;have&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just realize that there are pitfalls to the code coverage metric and be aware of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Continuous Integration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There should be a
&lt;a href="http://martinfowler.com/articles/continuousIntegration.html"&gt;continuous integration&lt;/a&gt;
environment set up for the code base.  Whether you set this up or the contractor
really doesn't matter, as long as you definitely have access to monitor it.  The
value to you as the company will be in the ability to monitor project progress,
monitor code coverage and other code quality metrics, and monitor the status of
the current build (code compiling and all tests passing).
&lt;a href="http://jenkins-ci.org"&gt;Jenkins&lt;/a&gt; is certainly the most main-stream CI
technology, and you can apparently get a hosted version
&lt;a href="http://www.cloudbees.com/jenkins-enterprise-by-cloudbees-overview.cb"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
Jenkins itself is free and open source, so you can deploy it to your own local
or cloud servers too.  Another interesting option might be
&lt;a href="http://travis-ci.com"&gt;Travis CI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DevOps considerations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DevOps tasks are all those that deal with keeping your software running
&lt;em&gt;in production&lt;/em&gt;. Are your servers healthy, or are they becoming overburdened?
Is your application even running, or has something crashed?  Your architecture
might be one that has several interdependent components, and that the front door
is working properly doesn't necessarily mean a portion of the system hasn't
crashed elsewhere.  Server and application health requires constant, automated
monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The area of DevOps is often separate from the software development itself.  Make
sure you have a DevOps strategy for system monitoring, and have the appropriate
knowledge or resources to take action when something fails.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="software management"></category><category term="contracting"></category></entry><entry><title>Room temperature and narrow intersubband electroluminescence from ZnCdSe/ZnCdMgSe quantum cascade laser structures</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2011/07/room-temperature-and-narrow-intersubband-electroluminescence-from-zncdsezncdmgse-quantum-cascade-laser-structures/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-07-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2011-07-29:publication/2011/07/room-temperature-and-narrow-intersubband-electroluminescence-from-zncdsezncdmgse-quantum-cascade-laser-structures/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We report ZnCdSe/ZnCdMgSe Quantum Cascade structures with “two-phonon” and
“bound-to-continuum” active region designs. The electroluminescence shows more
than 3 times higher luminescence efficiency and 40% narrower linewidth (&amp;lt;30 meV)
than previous reports. The measured turn-on voltage matches closely the
calculated value, indicating the improved electron transport characteristics in
these structures. A waveguide design suitable for mode confinement in this
material system is also presented, which resulted in a structure with a single
narrow electroluminescence peak for all temperatures from 80 to 300 K.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="QCLs"></category><category term="II-VI semiconductors"></category><category term="lasers"></category></entry><entry><title>Growth of Znx'Cd1−x′Se/ZnxCdyMg1−x−ySe–InP quantum cascade structures for emission in the 3–5 μm range</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2010/03/growth-of-znxcd1-xseznxcdymg1-x-yse-inp-quantum-cascade-structures-for-emission-in-the-3-5-mm-range/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2010-03-23:publication/2010/03/growth-of-znxcd1-xseznxcdymg1-x-yse-inp-quantum-cascade-structures-for-emission-in-the-3-5-mm-range/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The molecular beam epitaxial growth and electroluminescence (EL) properties of
Zn&lt;sub&gt;0.48&lt;/sub&gt;Cd&lt;sub&gt;0.52&lt;/sub&gt;Se/Zn&lt;sub&gt;0.24&lt;/sub&gt;Cd&lt;sub&gt;0.18&lt;/sub&gt;Mg&lt;sub&gt;0.58&lt;/sub&gt;Se
quantum cascade (QC) structures are reported. The samples were composed of 30
repeats of a three-well active region. Cladding layers were inserted to isolate
the core of the EL structure from the heavily doped contact region and to obtain
optical confinement. Electroluminescence was observed in the 4–5 μm range. The
observed narrowing of the electroluminescence linewidth was tentatively
attributed, in part, to the incorporation of the ZnCdMgSe waveguide layers. A
test sample consisting of multiple asymmetric coupled quantum well active
regions separated by quaternary barrier layers was also investigated. The
Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) absorption spectroscopy measurements suggest
that QC structures with EL emission in the 3–4 μm range can be achieved with
these materials.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="II-VI semiconductors"></category><category term="molecular beam epitaxy"></category><category term="QCLs"></category></entry><entry><title>Short Injector Quantum Cascade Lasers</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2010/02/short-injector-quantum-cascade-lasers/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-25T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2010-02-25:publication/2010/02/short-injector-quantum-cascade-lasers/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We report our study on the effects of shortened quantum cascade (QC) laser
injector regions. While conventional short-wavelength QC lasers typically have
around seven or more injector region quantum wells, we investigate QC structures
with three and two injector wells. Improvements in threshold currents, output
powers, and wall-plug efficiencies are expected for fundamental reasons. At heat
sink temperatures near 80 K, we observe threshold current densities less than
0.5 kA/cm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;, nearly 4 W peak output power, and wall-plug efficiencies
in excess of 20%. At room temperature, we see threshold current densities around
2.3 kA/cm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;, output powers in excess of 1 W, and wall-plug
efficiencies around 7.6%. We also observe new effects in midinfrared QC lasers,
such as a pronounced negative differential resistance, pulse instabilities, and
multiple and varied turn-off mechanisms. These effects result from the greatly
abbreviated injector regions with highly discrete states.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="QCLs"></category><category term="lasers"></category></entry><entry><title>Highly Power-efficient Quantum Cascade Lasers</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2010/01/highly-power-efficient-quantum-cascade-lasers/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-10T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2010-01-10:publication/2010/01/highly-power-efficient-quantum-cascade-lasers/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Quantum cascade lasers are promising mid-infrared semiconductor light sources
for molecular detection in applications such as environmental sensing or
medical diagnostics. For such applications, researchers have been striving to
improve device performance. Recently, improvements in wall plug efficiency have
been pursued with a view to realizing compact, portable, power-efficient and
high-power quantum cascade laser systems. However, advances have largely been
incremental, and the basic quantum design has remained unchanged for many years,
with the wall plug efficiency yet to reach above 35%. A crucial factor in
quantum cascade laser performance is the efficient transport of electrons into
the laser active regions. We recently theoretically described this transport
process as limited by the interface-roughness-induced detuning of resonant
tunnelling. Here, we report that an ‘ultrastrong coupling’ design strategy
overcomes this limiting factor and leads to the experimental realization of
quantum cascade lasers with 40–50% wall plug efficiency when operated in pulsed
mode at temperatures of 160 K or lower.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="QCLs"></category><category term="lasers"></category></entry><entry><title>A widely voltage-tunable quantum cascade laser based on 'two-step' coupling</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2009/07/a-widely-voltage-tunable-quantum-cascade-laser-based-on-two-step-coupling/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-07-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2009-07-14:publication/2009/07/a-widely-voltage-tunable-quantum-cascade-laser-based-on-two-step-coupling/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A novel quantum cascade laser design with "two-step" coupling between the
injector and the upper laser state is demonstrated to achieve a widely
voltage-tunable laser spectrum. Electroluminescence from this design can be
tuned over a range of more than 200 cm&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; with a tuning coefficient of
~700 cm&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;/V per stage. Lasers based on this design provide a tuning range of
~100 cm&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; (8.3–9 µm) above threshold with a tuning coefficient of
~900 cm&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;/V per stage at a constant temperature of 295 K.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="QCLs"></category><category term="lasers"></category><category term="spectral tuning"></category></entry><entry><title>Quantum cascade lasers with voltage defect of less than one longitudinal optical phonon energy</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2009/06/quantum-cascade-lasers-with-voltage-defect-of-less-than-one-longitudinal-optical-phonon-energy/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-06-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2009-06-25:publication/2009/06/quantum-cascade-lasers-with-voltage-defect-of-less-than-one-longitudinal-optical-phonon-energy/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Efficient use of applied voltage in quantum cascade (QC) lasers is a critical
factor in achieving high wall-plug efficiency and low compliance voltage. We
demonstrate a QC laser emitting at 4.2 µm featuring a low voltage defect and
short injector with only four quantum wells. Devices with a voltage defect of
20 meV, well below the energy of the longitudinal optical phonons, and a voltage
efficiency of 91%, a record value for QC lasers, are reported for pulsed
operation at 180 K. Voltage efficiencies of greater than 80% are exhibited at
room temperature. Overall performance showed wall-plug efficiencies ranging
from 21% at cryogenic temperatures to 5.3% at room temperature.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="phonons"></category><category term="QCLs"></category><category term="lasers"></category></entry><entry><title>Mid-infrared Semiconductor Optical Metamaterials</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2009/06/mid-infrared-semiconductor-optical-metamaterials/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-06-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2009-06-18:publication/2009/06/mid-infrared-semiconductor-optical-metamaterials/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We report on a novel class of semiconductor metamaterials that employ a strongly
anisotropic dielectric function to achieve negative refraction in the
midinfrared region of the spectrum, ~8.5–13 µm. We present two types of
metamaterials, layered highly doped/undoped heterostructures and quantum well
superlattices that are highly anisotropic. Contrary to other optical
metamaterials these heterostructure systems are optically thick (up to 20 µm
thick), planar, and require no additional fabrication steps beyond the initial
growth. Using transmission and reflection measurements and modeling of the
highly doped heterostructures, we demonstrate that these materials exhibit
negative refraction. For the highly doped quantum well superlattices, we
demonstrate anomalous reflection due to the strong anisotropy of the material
but a determination of the sign of refraction is still difficult. This new
class of semiconductor metamaterials has great potential for waveguiding and
imaging applications in the long-wave infrared.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="metamaterials"></category><category term="semiconductors"></category></entry><entry><title>New Quantum Cascade Laser Architectures</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2009/06/new-quantum-cascade-laser-architectures/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2009-06-01:publication/2009/06/new-quantum-cascade-laser-architectures/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Quantum cascade (QC) lasers are today’s most capable mid-infrared light sources.
With up to watt-level room temperature emission over a broad swath of
mid-infrared wavelengths, these tiny semiconductor devices enable a variety of
applications and technologies such as ultra-sensitive systems for detecting
trace molecules in the vapor phase. The foundation of a QC structure lies in
alternating hundreds of wide- and narrow-bandgap semiconductor layers to form a
coupled quantum well system. In this way, the laws of quantum mechanics are used
to precisely engineer electron transport and create artificial optical
transitions. The result is a material with capabilities not found in nature,
a truly "designer" material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a central theme in this thesis, we stress the remarkable flexibility of the
quantum cascade—the ability to highly tailor device structure for creative
design concepts. The QC idea, in fact, relies on no particular material system
for its implementation. While all QC lasers to date have been fabricated from
III–V materials such as InGaAs/AlInAs, I detail our preliminary work on
ZnCdSe/ZnCdMgSe—a II–VI materials system—where we have demonstrated
electroluminescence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then further discuss how the inherent QC flexibility can be exploited for
new devices that extend QC performance and capabilities. In this regard, we
offer the examples of excited state transitions and short injectors. Excited
state transitions are an avenue to enhancing optical gain, which is especially
needed for longer-wavelength devices where optical losses hinder performance.
Likewise, shortening the QC injector length over a conventional QC structure has
powerful implications for threshold current, output power, and wall-plug
efficiency. In both cases, novel physical effects are discovered. Pumping
electrons into highly excited states led to the discovery of high k- space
lasing from highly non-equilibrium electron distributions. Shortening QC
injector regions allowed us to observe “classical” superlattice effects such as
negative differential resistance and pulse instabilities. While interesting from
a scientific perspective, these unique phenomena shed new insight on internal
QC laser processes and may them- selves lead to further improvements in device
performance.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="lasers"></category><category term="QCLs"></category><category term="thesis"></category></entry><entry><title>Voltage Tunability of Quantum Cascade Lasers</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2009/05/voltage-tunability-of-quantum-cascade-lasers/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-05-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2009-05-19:publication/2009/05/voltage-tunability-of-quantum-cascade-lasers/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The voltage tunability of three types of quantum cascade laser designs is
investigated. The tuning coefficients and tuning ranges of electroluminescence
and laser emission from all designs are measured and compared with the
calculated results. A reduced tunability was observed in all lasers above
threshold. This is attributed to the decrease of resistance across the laser
active region (AR) as the photon density increases. A resumed tunability high
above threshold occurs in all lasers with anticrossed injector ground and upper
laser states. Lasers based on the anticrossed diagonal transition are tunable
above threshold, with a tuning range of about 30 cm&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; (~3% of the laser emission
wavenumber), i.e., a tuning rate of
750 cm&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;V&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;•period&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; of the AR and the injector.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="lasers"></category><category term="QCLs"></category><category term="spectral tuning"></category></entry><entry><title>Wide Band Gap II-VI Selenides for Short Wavelength Intersubband Devices</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2009/03/wide-band-gap-ii-vi-selenides-for-short-wavelength-intersubband-devices/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-03-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2009-03-15:publication/2009/03/wide-band-gap-ii-vi-selenides-for-short-wavelength-intersubband-devices/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we present our recent progress towards the realization of short
wavelength intersubband devices with wide band gap II-VI selenide
semiconductors. Intersubband electroluminescence at 4.8 μm was observed in a
ZnCdSe/ZnCdMgSe quantum cascade structure at temperatures up to room
temperature. We also developed a new ZnCdSe/MgSe quantum structure with
metastable MgSe barriers. Intersubband absorption in the 3-5 μm range was
observed. Calculations suggest that with this structure intersubband transitions
as short as 1.55 μm may be achieved.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="II-VI semiconductors"></category><category term="optoelectronics"></category></entry><entry><title>Wavelength selection for quantum cascade lasers by cavity length</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2009/03/wavelength-selection-for-quantum-cascade-lasers-by-cavity-length/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-03-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2009-03-04:publication/2009/03/wavelength-selection-for-quantum-cascade-lasers-by-cavity-length/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A systematic shift in spectral emission wavenumbers in quantum cascade lasers
(QCLs) is observed over a variation in cavity lengths from 0.5 to 3 mm resulting
in a gain peak shift ranging from 2404 to 2286 cm&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt;. Thereby, a wavelength
selection range of 118 cm&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; is provided, which is sufficiently broad
for selecting the laser emission across the entire CO2 absorption band at
2326 cm&lt;sup&gt;−1&lt;/sup&gt; (4.3 µm). In contrast to current QCL wavelength selection
techniques, modifying the cavity length is a straightforward postprocessing
procedure. Experimental evidence confirms that this frequency shift is due to a
change in threshold voltage and applied electric field as a function of cavity
length which is in agreement with the theory.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="lasers"></category><category term="QCLs"></category><category term="infrared spectroscopy"></category></entry><entry><title>Role of interface roughness in the transport and lasing characteristics of quantum-cascade lasers</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2009/03/role-of-interface-roughness-in-the-transport-and-lasing-characteristics-of-quantum-cascade-lasers/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-03-03T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2009-03-03:publication/2009/03/role-of-interface-roughness-in-the-transport-and-lasing-characteristics-of-quantum-cascade-lasers/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A density-matrix based theory of transport and lasing in quantum-cascade lasers reveals that large disparity between luminescent linewidth and broadening of the tunneling transition changes the design guidelines to favor strong coupling between injector and upper laser level. This conclusion is supported by the experimental evidence.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="lasers"></category><category term="electron transport"></category><category term="QCLs"></category></entry><entry><title>Voltage tuning of gain spectra in quantum cascade lasers</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2009/02/voltage-tuning-of-gain-spectra-in-quantum-cascade-lasers/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-02-03T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2009-02-03:publication/2009/02/voltage-tuning-of-gain-spectra-in-quantum-cascade-lasers/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The voltage tuning of gain spectra in three types of Quantum Cascade laser
designs is investigated. The gain spectra of the luminescence device are tunable
over the whole voltage operation range for all designs. The lasers are as
tunable as the electroluminescence below threshold, while a reduced tunability
is observed in all lasers above threshold. This is attributed to the decrease of
resistance across the laser active region as the photon density increases. A
resumed tunability high above threshold occurs in all lasers based on the
anti-crossed designs. Lasers based on the anti-crossed diagonal transition are
tunable above threshold, with a tuning range of about 40 cm&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; (~4% of the laser
emission wavenumber) at room temperature, i.e. a tuning rate of
800 cm&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; per volt per period of active region and injector.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="QCLs"></category><category term="lasers"></category></entry><entry><title>Lasing-induced reduction of core heating in high wall plug efficiency quantum cascade lasers</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2009/01/lasing-induced-reduction-of-core-heating-in-high-wall-plug-efficiency-quantum-cascade-lasers/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-01-26T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2009-01-26:publication/2009/01/lasing-induced-reduction-of-core-heating-in-high-wall-plug-efficiency-quantum-cascade-lasers/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Quantum cascade (QC) laser core heating is a primary impediment to high device
wall plug efficiency (WPE). Here, we demonstrate that efficient photon
generation produces a quantifiable reduction in heating of the QC laser core
temperature. By superimposing low duty cycle current pulses on a core-heating
dc baseline, we observe the instantaneous threshold current and current
efficiency evolution as the dc input is varied. From these measurements we
recover the laser core temperature &lt;em&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;core&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Results agree well with calculations
of &lt;em&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;core&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt; based on measured thermal resistance and WPE. Using the
same thermal model for a laser with negligible WPE, we show that the large
WPE of the measured device-—24% for an 80 K heat sink-—results in a core
temperature reduction of ~15 K.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="QCLs"></category><category term="lasers"></category></entry><entry><title>High k-space lasing in a dual wavelength quantum cascade laser</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2008/12/high-k-space-lasing-in-a-dual-wavelength-quantum-cascade-laser/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-12-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2008-12-14:publication/2008/12/high-k-space-lasing-in-a-dual-wavelength-quantum-cascade-laser/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We report on a quantum cascade (QC) laser structure with an energy configuration
able to establish local population inversion of electrons high in &lt;em&gt;k&lt;/em&gt;-space
through intrinsic processes. We observe dual wavelength emission from two
discrete optical transitions lasing near &lt;em&gt;λ&lt;/em&gt; ≈ 9.5 and 8.2 µm.
Temperature-dependent performance attributes show that the two transitions are
highly coupled: competition for charge carriers is apparent from anti-correlated
behaviour in output power. The anti-correlated behaviour is further observed
through the temperature dependence of threshold currents, with the secondary
transition having a negative characteristic temperature T&lt;sub&gt;0&lt;/sub&gt; before it sharply
becomes positive. The two optical transitions represent a conventional QC laser
transition at &lt;em&gt;k&lt;/em&gt; ≈ 0 and another laser transition from non-thermal electrons at
k ≈ 3.6×108 m&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="lasers"></category><category term="QCLs"></category><category term="phonons"></category></entry><entry><title>Molecular Beam Epitaxy Growth of ZnxCd1-xSe/Znx'Cdy'Mg1-x'-y'Se-InP Quantum Cascade Structures</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2008/12/molecular-beam-epitaxy-growth-of-znxcd1-xseznxcdymg1-x-yse-inp-quantum-cascade-structures/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2008-12-01:publication/2008/12/molecular-beam-epitaxy-growth-of-znxcd1-xseznxcdymg1-x-yse-inp-quantum-cascade-structures/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We report growth by molecular beam epitaxy of a
Zn&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;Cd&lt;sub&gt;1-x&lt;/sub&gt;Se/Zn&lt;sub&gt;x'&lt;/sub&gt;Cd&lt;sub&gt;y'&lt;/sub&gt;Mg&lt;sub&gt;1-x'-y'&lt;/sub&gt;Se
quantum cascade (QC) structure that was
designed for electroluminescence (EL) at ~4.5 µm. The QC active region is
comprised of a two-well asymmetric coupled quantum well (ACQW) structure, which
was thoroughly investigated to establish the growth conditions for the QC
structure. After growth of several ACQW test samples, the conditions for growth
were optimized for the QC structure. In-situ RHEED, photoluminescence (PL),
high-resolution X-ray diffraction (HR-XRD) and Fourier transform infrared (FTIR)
spectroscopy results were used for characterization. The QC structure grown
under these conditions exhibited EL at 4.8 µm, in excellent agreement with the
design value.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="II-VI semiconductors"></category><category term="molecular beam epitaxy"></category><category term="QCLs"></category></entry><entry><title>The effect of injector barrier thickness and doping level on current transport and optical transition width in a λ ~ 8 µm QC structure</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2008/11/the-effect-of-injector-barrier-thickness-and-doping-level-on-current-transport-and-optical-transition-width-in-a-l-8-um-qc-structure/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-11-12T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2008-11-12:publication/2008/11/the-effect-of-injector-barrier-thickness-and-doping-level-on-current-transport-and-optical-transition-width-in-a-l-8-um-qc-structure/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We experimentally study the optical transition width and current transport
properties of a set of λ~8.0 µm quantum cascade (QC) structures with varying
injector barrier thickness and doping level. For this high-performance QC laser
structure, a 50% reduction in doping level and a 33% reduction in injection
barrier thickness yield five times stronger luminescence, 20% smaller optical
transition linewidth, and improved current-voltage characteristics. These
results demonstrate how high-performance QC laser structures can be engineered
to produce narrow gain spectra at and above room temperature.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="lasers"></category><category term="QCLs"></category></entry><entry><title>Growth and Characterization of ZnxCd1-xSe/Znx’Cdy’Mg1-x’-y’Se Asymmetric Coupled Quantum Well Structures for Quantum Cascade Laser Applications</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2008/05/growth-and-characterization-of-znxcd1-xseznxcdymg1-x-yse-asymmetric-coupled-quantum-well-structures-for-quantum-cascade-laser-applications/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-05-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2008-05-30:publication/2008/05/growth-and-characterization-of-znxcd1-xseznxcdymg1-x-yse-asymmetric-coupled-quantum-well-structures-for-quantum-cascade-laser-applications/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The authors report the growth of a II-VI
Zn&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;Cd&lt;sub&gt;1-x&lt;/sub&gt;Se/Zn&lt;sub&gt;x’&lt;/sub&gt;Cd&lt;sub&gt;y’&lt;/sub&gt;Mg&lt;sub&gt;1-x’-y’&lt;/sub&gt;Se
asymmetric coupled quantum well (asymmetric-CQW) structure that was used to
investigate the active region of an intersubband electroluminescence structure
designed for emission at λ=4.5 µm. Such a structure could comprise the active
region of a quantum cascade laser. The results of photoluminescence and Fourier
transform infrared spectroscopy analysis show good agreement with the expected
transition energies predicted by simulation results for the asymmetric-CQW
structure. High resolution x-ray diffraction analysis indicates high structural
quality of the sample and good control of the growth.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="II-VI semiconductors"></category><category term="molecular beam epitaxy"></category><category term="QCLs"></category></entry><entry><title>ZnCdSe/ZnCdMgSe Quantum Cascade Electroluminescence</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2008/03/zncdsezncdmgse-quantum-cascade-electroluminescence/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-03-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2008-03-25:publication/2008/03/zncdsezncdmgse-quantum-cascade-electroluminescence/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This letter reports electroluminescence emission from a ZnCdSe/ZnCdMgSe quantum
cascade (QC) structure. With a two-well QC active region design, the II-VI
heterostructure was grown lattice matched on an InP substrate by molecular beam
epitaxy. Deep etched mesas were electrically pumped at current densities up to
10 kA/cm, producing optical emission centered near 4.8 µm, in good agreement
with the structure design. The light is predominantly TM polarized, confirming
its intersubband origin. Electroluminescence was observed from 78 to 300 K.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="II-VI semiconductors"></category><category term="QCLs"></category><category term="optoelectronics"></category></entry><entry><title>Low voltage-defect quantum cascade laser with heterogeneous injector regions</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2007/11/low-voltage-defect-quantum-cascade-laser-with-heterogeneous-injector-regions/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-11-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2007-11-14:publication/2007/11/low-voltage-defect-quantum-cascade-laser-with-heterogeneous-injector-regions/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We demonstrate an In&lt;sub&gt;0.635&lt;/sub&gt;Al&lt;sub&gt;0.356&lt;/sub&gt;As/In&lt;sub&gt;0.678&lt;/sub&gt;Ga&lt;sub&gt;0.322&lt;/sub&gt;As
strain compensated quantum cascade laser that employs heterogeneous injector
regions for low voltage defect operation. The active core consists of
interdigitated undoped and doped injectors followed by nominally identical
wavelength optical transitions. The undoped injector regions are designed with
reduced voltage defect while the doped injectors are of a more conventional
design. The measured average voltage defect is less than 79 meV. At 80 K, a
2.3 mm long, back facet high reflectance coated laser has an emission wavelength
of 4.7 μm and outputs 2.3 W pulsed power with a peak wall-plug efficiency of
19%.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="lasers"></category><category term="QCLs"></category></entry><entry><title>Negative refraction in semiconductor metamaterials</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2007/10/negative-refraction-in-semiconductor-metamaterials/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-10-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2007-10-14:publication/2007/10/negative-refraction-in-semiconductor-metamaterials/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An optical metamaterial is a composite in which subwavelength features, rather
than the constituent materials, control the macroscopic electromagnetic
properties of the material. Recently, properly designed metamaterials have
garnered much interest because of their unusual interaction with electromagnetic
waves. Whereas nature seems to have limits on the type of materials that exist,
newly invented metamaterials are not bound by such constraints. These newly
accessible electromagnetic properties make these materials an excellent platform
for demonstrating unusual optical phenomena and unique applications such as
subwavelength imaging and planar lens design. 'Negative-index materials', as
first proposed, required the permittivity and permeability to be simultaneously
less than zero, but such materials face limitations. Here, we demonstrate a
comparatively low-loss, three-dimensional, all-semiconductor metamaterial that
exhibits negative refraction for all incidence angles in the long-wave infrared
region and requires only an anisotropic dielectric function with a single
resonance. Using reflection and transmission measurements and a comprehensive
model of the material, we demonstrate that our material exhibits negative
refraction. This is furthermore confirmed through a straightforward beam optics
experiment.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="metamaterials"></category><category term="negative refractive index"></category><category term="semiconductors"></category></entry><entry><title>Optical Properties of Heavily Doped n-type CdSe Quantum Dots for Intersubband Device Applications</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2007/09/optical-properties-of-heavily-doped-n-type-cdse-quantum-dots-for-intersubband-device-applications/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-09-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2007-09-06:publication/2007/09/optical-properties-of-heavily-doped-n-type-cdse-quantum-dots-for-intersubband-device-applications/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this research, interband and intersubband optical properties of heavily doped
n-type CdSe quantum dots were investigated by temperature dependent
photoluminescence (PL) spectroscopy, picosecond time-resolved PL spectroscopy
and Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy. Two doped and one undoped
CdSe quantum dot samples with multiple QD layers were grown over ZnCdMgSe
barrier layers on InP (001) substrate by molecular beam epitaxy. Heavy doping
leads to decreasing of activation energy of nonradiative recombination centers,
however, does not affect the luminescence efficiency of doped quantum dots. Time
resolved PL experiments show that the PL decay times of the doped samples have
weak dependence on dot size and are much longer than that of the undoped sample.
The two doped CdSe QD samples show strong intersubband IR absorption that peaked
at 2.54 μm, 2.69 μm and 3.51 μm.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="quantum dots"></category><category term="II-VI semiconductors"></category></entry><entry><title>Intersubband transitions in molecular-beam-epitaxy-grown wide band gap II-VI semiconductors</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2007/05/intersubband-transitions-in-molecular-beam-epitaxy-grown-wide-band-gap-ii-vi-semiconductors/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-05-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2007-05-31:publication/2007/05/intersubband-transitions-in-molecular-beam-epitaxy-grown-wide-band-gap-ii-vi-semiconductors/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The authors report the study of intersubband transitions in ZnCdMgSe-based wide
band gap II-VI semiconductors. The samples were prepared by molecular beam
epitaxy on InP substrates. Both ZnCdSe/ZnCdMgSe multiple quantum wells and
CdSe/ZnCdMgSe quantum dot multilayer stacks were grown. Strong intersubband
absorption was observed in the samples. The results show that these materials
are very promising for fabricating intersubband devices in the mid- and
near-infrared spectral ranges.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="II-VI semiconductors"></category><category term="molecular beam epitaxy"></category></entry><entry><title>Study of intersubband transitions of ZnxCd1−xSe/Znx'Cdy'Mg1−x'−y'Se multiple quantum wells grown by molecular beam epitaxy for midinfrared device applications</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2007/05/study-of-intersubband-transitions-of-znxcd1-xseznxcdymg1-x-yse-multiple-quantum-wells-grown-by-molecular-beam-epitaxy-for-midinfrared-device-applications/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-05-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2007-05-31:publication/2007/05/study-of-intersubband-transitions-of-znxcd1-xseznxcdymg1-x-yse-multiple-quantum-wells-grown-by-molecular-beam-epitaxy-for-midinfrared-device-applications/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two Zn&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;Cd&lt;sub&gt;1−x&lt;/sub&gt;Se/Zn&lt;sub&gt;x'&lt;/sub&gt;Cd&lt;sub&gt;y'&lt;/sub&gt;Mg&lt;sub&gt;1−x'−y'&lt;/sub&gt;Se
multiple quantum well structures were grown by molecular beam epitaxy. The
quantum well layer thickness of the multiple quantum well region was varied in
order to tune the intersubband transition energy. The high crystalline quality
of the material was demonstrated by high resolution x-ray diffraction.
Contactless electroreflectance (CER) spectroscopy and Fourier transform infrared
(FTIR) spectroscopy were used to characterize the intersubband transitions.
Excellent agreement between the estimated value obtained by CER and the value
measured by FTIR was achieved. Intersubband absorption at 6.89 and 5.37 µm was
observed demonstrating the ability to tune the properties of these wide band
gap II-VI materials for mid-IR intersubband device applications.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="II-VI semiconductors"></category><category term="quantum wells"></category></entry><entry><title>Evidence of cascaded emission in a dual-wavelength Quantum Cascade laser</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2007/02/evidence-of-cascaded-emission-in-a-dual-wavelength-quantum-cascade-laser/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-02-28T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2007-02-28:publication/2007/02/evidence-of-cascaded-emission-in-a-dual-wavelength-quantum-cascade-laser/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This letter reports on a quantum cascade laser that exhibits simultaneous
dual-wavelength emission from two consecutive optical transitions in each active
region. These "cascaded" transitions—a second-excited state to first-excited
state and a first-excited state to ground state—yield light at ~9.5 and ~8.2 µm,
respectively, in good agreement with simulations. The two lasing wavelengths
have similar thresholds at the leading edge of a current pulse.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="lasers"></category><category term="QCLs"></category></entry><entry><title>Intersubband absorption in CdSe/ZnCdMgSe self-assembled quantum dot multi-layers</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2007/02/intersubband-absorption-in-cdsezncdmgse-self-assembled-quantum-dot-multi-layers/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-02-15T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2007-02-15:publication/2007/02/intersubband-absorption-in-cdsezncdmgse-self-assembled-quantum-dot-multi-layers/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The authors report the observation of intersubband absorption in multilayers of
CdSe/Zn&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;Cd&lt;sub&gt;y&lt;/sub&gt;Mg&lt;sub&gt;1−x−y&lt;/sub&gt;Se self-assembled quantum
dots. The samples were grown by molecular beam epitaxy on InP substrates. For
samples with the CdSe dot layers doped with Cl and with the deposited CdSe
equivalent layer thickness between 5.2 and 6.9 ML, peak absorption between 2.5
and 3.5 µm was observed. These materials are promising for intersubband devices
operating in the mid- and near-infrared ranges.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="quantum dots"></category><category term="II-VI semiconductors"></category></entry><entry><title>Optical characterization of intersubband transitions in ZnxCd1−xSe/Znx'Cdy'Mg1−x'−y'Se multiple quantum well structures by contactless electroreflectance</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2006/12/optical-characterization-of-intersubband-transitions-in-znxcd1-xseznxcdymg1-x-yse-multiple-quantum-well-structures-by-contactless-electroreflectance/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2006-12-15T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2006-12-15:publication/2006/12/optical-characterization-of-intersubband-transitions-in-znxcd1-xseznxcdymg1-x-yse-multiple-quantum-well-structures-by-contactless-electroreflectance/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Contactless electroreflectance was measured at room temperature to characterize
a wide range of the possible optical transitions in
Zn&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;Cd&lt;sub&gt;1−x&lt;/sub&gt;Se/Zn&lt;sub&gt;x'&lt;/sub&gt;Cd&lt;sub&gt;y'&lt;/sub&gt;Mg&lt;sub&gt;1−x'−y'&lt;/sub&gt;Se
multi-quantum-well structures grown by molecular beam epitaxy. Based on these
measurements, the authors predict and then verify the anticipated intersubband
transition energies. They investigate a representative
Zn&lt;sub&gt;0.5&lt;/sub&gt;Cd&lt;sub&gt;0.5&lt;/sub&gt;Se/Zn&lt;sub&gt;0.20&lt;/sub&gt;Cd&lt;sub&gt;0.19&lt;/sub&gt;Mg&lt;sub&gt;0.61&lt;/sub&gt;Se
structure, for which the &lt;em&gt;E1&lt;/em&gt;-&lt;em&gt;E2&lt;/em&gt; transition energy is predicted to be 178 meV
(6.97 µm). Intersubband absorption using Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy
exhibits a peak at 180 meV (6.89 µm), in excellent agreement with the
contactless electroreflectance measurements.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="II-VI semiconductors"></category><category term="optoelectronics"></category></entry><entry><title>A dual-wavelength quantum cascade laser with two optical transitions in each active region</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2006/05/a-dual-wavelength-quantum-cascade-laser-with-two-optical-transitions-in-each-active-region/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2006-05-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2006-05-07:publication/2006/05/a-dual-wavelength-quantum-cascade-laser-with-two-optical-transitions-in-each-active-region/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We report on a novel quantum cascade laser design that utilizes wide active
region quantum wells to create a lasing transition between the second- and
first-excited states of the constituent wells. Electroluminescence and lasing
spectra confirm the presence of the optical transition at the expected energy,
but also show the conventional transition between energy levels resulting from
excited and ground states of the original quantum wells. As a result, the laser
produces simultaneous dual-wavelength emission at 8.2 μm and 9.3 μm.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="QCLs"></category><category term="lasers"></category></entry><entry><title>Carbon single-wall nanotube growth in a volumetrically confined arc discharge system</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2004/08/carbon-single-wall-nanotube-growth-in-a-volumetrically-confined-arc-discharge-system/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2004-08-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2004-08-01:publication/2004/08/carbon-single-wall-nanotube-growth-in-a-volumetrically-confined-arc-discharge-system/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Carbon nanotubes hold significant promise for a vast number of materials
applications due to their unique mechanical, electrical, and gas storage
properties. Although carbon single-wall nanotubes (SWNTs) have been synthesized
since 1993 by the arc discharge method, and numerous other synthesis methods
have since been developed, no method has yet produced 100% pure carbon
nanotubes. Instead, a significant amount of impurities—various carbon structures
and metal catalysts—are present in the raw soot. While arc discharge was the
first method for SWNT synthesis, it also produces more impure raw soot in
comparison to the more recently developed laser vaporization, which has produced
the purest raw soot to date but is much slower. Geometry and thermal gradient
are appreciably different between traditional arc discharge systems and laser
vaporization systems. We report that, by incorporating some characteristics
inherent to a laser vaporization system into an arc discharge system,
improvement in the yield of SWNT raw soot may be achieved. This is accomplished
by confining the arc within a 50 mm diameter quartz tube, similar to laser
vaporization. We find through transmission electron microscopy and Raman
spectroscopy that SWNTs are made in significant numbers in this confined arc
discharge system, comparable to laser vaporization synthesized material. Further
study is, however, required to prove reproducibility and attain an exact value
for the purity of the produced raw soot.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="carbon nanotubes"></category></entry><entry><title>DNA Dilemma: A perspective on U.S. Patent and Trademark Office philosophy concerning life patents</title><link href="http://notinkansasnow.com/publication/2002/08/dna-dilemma-a-perspective-on-us-patent-and-trademark-office-philosophy-concerning-life-patents/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2002-08-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Kale J. Franz, PhD</name></author><id>tag:notinkansasnow.com,2002-08-01:publication/2002/08/dna-dilemma-a-perspective-on-us-patent-and-trademark-office-philosophy-concerning-life-patents/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The lack of a solid set of criteria for determining patentability of subject
matter—particularly subject matter dealing with life—has recently been of
increasing public concern in the United States. Alarm for patent practices
related to life systems ranges from patents being granted on
biochemical processes and the knowledge of these processes to the patenting of
entire organisms. One of the most volatile concerns is the patenting of human
genes or parts of genes since this genetic material is the basic informational
molecule for all life. Current patent law, legislated in 1952, has been
interpreted by the U.S. Supreme Court to allow broad patents of DNA, biochemical
processes, and what are generally considered "inventions" of life systems.
Several issues are addressed in this paper regarding the unsound reasoning
underlying both the interpretation and execution of patent law. Lapses in logic
provide a gateway for businesses and individuals to take patenting to an
illogical and unworkable extreme. Patent Office disorder of this magnitude is
unnecessary and has great potential for harming the mission that the patent
office was designed to serve. Recently disclosed patent-granting guidelines
suggest the United States Patent and Trademark Office is not upholding its
Constitutional responsibility of promoting the progress of science.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="patents"></category><category term="dna"></category></entry></feed>